Jury Alyavdin

Lead Product Designer i-alvavdin.com

in/j-alyavdin mail@jalyavdin.ru +34 698999828

About

A Barcelona-based Digital Product Designer with ten years of experience in developing business-oriented products that help advanced enterprise companies and startups achieve their goals and grow faster. Passionate about gathering information from different sources into one clear picture and making complex systems easier to use.

Experience

Impress

Lead Product Designer
June 2020 — Current

I am building a design and research department in the European leader in the orthodontic sector startup. My main focus is clarifying expectations between the product team and stakeholders and bringing the design culture to the company's environment.

Yandex

Senior Product Designer March 2017 — June 2020 As a member of the experimental team, I found the PMF for the branch of the mobile application that increased revenue four times and made it mainstream of the whole e-commerce business unit in the giant technology company.

Rambler Group

Product Designer
May 2016 — March 2017

Launched three new media platforms and increased the revenue from ads in 12 existing media services in major media holding in Russia.

Zvooq

Product Designer
April 2016 — May 2016

Launched a service for using the content of one of the leading Russian streaming services on partner resources to increase the coverage of the service audience.

Webinar

Product Designer February 2015 — April 2016 In collaboration with a digital agency, relaunched and scaled the product line for the most famous Russian video streaming service.

Zelenski

Product Designer December 2013 — February 2015 Improved user experience across eight travel services for one of the industry leaders in travel solutions.

Education

Yandex Courses

Public speaking

Yandex Courses

Jobs to be Done: Theory to Practice 2017

Yandex School of Data Analysis Designing mobile apps

2017

Microsoft

Microsoft Inclusive Design, Industrial and Product Design 2016

Moscow State Technological University

Specialist Diploma in Engineering 2008 — 2013

Hight School №32 with advanced study of English

Foundation education 1997 — 2008

Skills

Product&Strategy

Defining goals and needs of the customers and business

Research

Identifying pains and problems and coming up with possible solutions

Prototyping

Hypothesis testing on customers at each fidelity step

Information Architecture

Organizing and structuring content and navigation

Technology&Data

Apprehending web and mobile development environment

Data-driven approach

Evaluating project success based on data analysis